SURAJ NAVAGIRE () Featured

Software Engineer with 4+ years of experience in core java and object oriented design. Having proficient knowledge of Core Java, Data Structure, REST, Spring, Hibernate, SQL, Oracle DB, Spark, Kafka. Love to solve problems.



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 4 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Current Company: SmartStream RDU Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Mumbai Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Mumbai, Pune

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: software developer,software development,data structure,design patterns,core java,rest

webservices, servlets, jpa, sql, oracle db, java, json, xml, problem

solving,learning,ORM,J2Ee,Multithreading,JDK,JDBC,Eclipse,Linux, Spark, kafka, Spring,

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

Application Developer in Oracle Financial Services Software Limited with 2 years of experience. Developed API?s with the help of JAVA, REST web services, SQL. Want to work in an environment where I can get new things to learn and new challenges to solve.

Work Experience

SmartStream RDU as Software Engineer

Mar 2019 to Till Date

Working in a product responsible for providing reference data of a financial securities listed on exchanges. Developed distributed engine for gathering and distributing reference data. Developed utility to compare big files such as xml, json, csv etc.

Oracle Financial Services Software as Application Developer -Core Java Aug 2016 to Feb 2019

Worked in a channel banking product.
Followed agile software development methodology.
Developed API using Java, REST web service, JPA and SQL as per the requirements.
Built Unit test cases for developed API.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Mumbai University in 2016

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
CORE JAVA			
REST Webservices			
Hibernate			0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
SQL, Oracle DB			
WebLogic			
Linux			
SPARK		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Apache Kafka		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
HTML, CSS, JAVA SCRIPT		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)
Mongodb		0	0 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Expert			
Marathi	Expert			

Projects

Project Title: Oracle Banking Digital Experience

Client: Cannot mention

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Aug 2016 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: It is a channel banking product used to onboard and service

customers from websites and mobile application.

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time